Contact

richspence@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/thisisrichie (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

HTML5

CSS

jQuery

Languages

JavaScript (Professional Working)

Honors-Awards

Google Developer Challenge Scholarship

Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree Scholarship (Google/ Udacity

Rich Spence

Developer I, Epsilon at Google

Santa Clara, California

Summary

I have over 3 years of experience as a front-end developer.

Currently, I work as a developer at Epsilon where I apply my coding skills to create beautiful user friendly email campaigns for various Google products and events.

Competencies: HTML,LESS,CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Python and Ethereum-Solidity (Blockchain)

Experience

Epsilon
Email Developer I
March 2018 - Present
San Francisco Bay Area

My role is to ensure that every email that was designed by our awesome creative team is perfected and responsive throughout all desktop and mobile platforms (including Outlook, Gmail, and Native). We work mainly with HTML, CSS/LESS, and Javascript. I enjoy working close with my team and I value the connections that are being made as well.

MaKaboom

Coding Instructor/Tutor
January 2018 - February 2018 (2 months)
Santa Clara, CA

I was apart of a small startup that provided education to youth ages 5-12 on basic computer science fundamentals, logic, and IoT classes.

I taught a variety of classes during my time with Makaboom that included, drone construction/programming and battle-bot construction/programming. Also, I took part in teaching at an annual summer camp in which there were more subjects taught, such as 3D printing programming and programming an animated game using 'Scratch'.

Codify Academy
Teaching Assistant
August 2017 - November 2017 (4 months)

San Francisco, California

Assist the lead mentor in teaching Bootcamp classes, teaching HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, JavaScript, Bootstrap, media queries, AngularJS, responsive design, web development best practices, and debugging techniques.

Help coordinate lessons, teach students how to tackle real-world coding challenges, monitor student progress, and provide additional assistance when necessary.

USA Track & Field Coach July 2014 - July 2017 (3 years 1 month) San Francisco Bay Area

Education

Blockgeeks

Blockchain technology (2018 - 2019)

Codify Academy

Computer Software Engineering · (2017 - 2017)

San Jose State University

Kinesiology and Exercise Science · (2016 - 2017)

City College of San Francisco

Associate of Science (A.S.), Kinesiology and Exercise Science · (2009 - 2012)

freeCodeCamp

Full Stack Web Development Certification, Computer Software Engineering · (2016 - 2017)